#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer – 6+ years building and servicing internal web apps for process standardization and efficiency – Passionate about developing apps which increase process effectiveness and help achieve maximum efficiency. Experienced with Git VCS, REACT/JSX, Redux, Angular JS, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Node JS, Express JS

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Black Flame Consulting**

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

84067 Roy, UT MAR 2017 – CURRENT

- •Crafted fundraising website for Endoderma skin treatment using HTML5, JSX, React, Redux, CSS3, ES6 JavaScript. VCS through Git.
- •Designed services and information website for Transperitive Coaching using React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, ES6 JavaScript. VCS through Git
- Assisted with development of open-source project GameFinder for Hitt Design using AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB, Node JS, Express, Git VCS.

#### **Esurance Inc**

CLIENT SERVICES SUPERVISOR

84401 OGDEN. UT

Jan 2014 - May 2017

- Raised Customer Service Quality scores by 20%+ by designing and creating web app to standardize noting procedures. Created using HTML5, CSS3, Open VCS, JavaScript, AngularJS.
- •Enhanced customer experience by authoring web application for procedure normalization of internal processing team. Designed with AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- •Increased underwriting department efficiency by designing JavaScript application to intuitively note and action accounts. Designed with Open VCS, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Decreased overall cost of operations through coaching strategies, procedure standardization and effective performance incentives.

# **Tim Dahle Imports**

INTERNET SALES ASSOCIATE

84107 Murray, UT

May 2013 - Nov 2013

•Increased online contact sale rate by 15% through Virtual Product Presentation initiative.

# eBay Inc

CUSTOMER SERVICE ASSOCIATE 3

84020 DRAPER, UT

Jun 2008 - Dec 2012

- •Established account noting standards by adapting web app to department needs. Created with Vanilla JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- •Reduced agent error by 30%+ for customer refund initiative by creating JavaScript web app input validation tool. Created with Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Macro-Express. Designed to collect input and submit HTTP requests with data collected.
- •Increased refund timeframe efficiency by creating web form for eBay Buyer Protection launch using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- •Ranked 99th percentile of agent performance by process efficiency and quality.

## **Bydex Management**

QUALITY ASSURANCE LEAD

84116 SALT LAKE CITY, UT

JAN 2007 - APR 2008

- •Created new QA definition criteria for sales and customer service agents.
- Designed and implemented monthly subscription call flow process for quality evaluation and grading.
- Upgraded existing call flow processes and evaluated effectiveness for sales and service organization.

#### EDUCATION

# **Bachelor of Science Business IT Management**

WESTERN GOVERNORS UNIVERSITY

Studied IT and database structure and TCP/IP theory

# Full Stack JavaScript Web Development V SCHOOL

Studied Full MEAN/MERN Stack JS frameworks

# **Project+ Project Management Certification**

**COMPTIA** 

Certified in initiating and managing projects/business initiatives

#### SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT; ES6
ANGULAR JS
JQUERY
HTML5/CSS3

REACT JS

NODE JS

EXPRESS JS

MS VISUAL STUDIO

MONGODB
MS EXCEL
PROJECT MANAGEMENT
GIT VCS

#### Portfolio Projects

MP3-Downloader | http://bit.ly/2sWJ6cl Single Page Application interacting with API's to search YouTube for a song, extract and download the audio, and also display lyrics and metadata for the track.

**Technologies Used**: AngularJS, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML5

BM Art | http://bit.ly/2thUw9E

C.R.U.D. application interacting with Burning Man API to find and save art projects into database. Designed to be responsive using bootstrap.

**Technologies Used**: AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML5, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS

JABBERTALKEE | HTTP://BIT.LY/2TICA3V

Full Stack CRUD chat application with user-auth. Allows creation of user accounts, private/public channels, and messages.

**Technologies Used**: AngularJS, Bootstrap, HTML5, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS